

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Senior Project Manager seeking roles in IT Infrastructure Management, Systems Security, Strategic Planning, Business Analysis, Software Development , QMS Implementation , Risk Assessment , QMS Implementation, Service Delivery, technical support



Total Experience: 15 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [Computer Applications]

Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Designation: Senior Project Manager-Engineering

/Program Manager

Current Company: Bharti Airtel Limited, Airtel Center

Current Location: Delhi

Pref. Location: INDIA, United Arab Emirates (UAE), United

Kingdom (UK)

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance
Role: Program Mgr
Industry: Telcom/ISP
Warital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Project Manager, Program Manager, IT Infrastructure Management, Systems Security, Strategic Planning, Business Analysis, Software Development, QMS Implementation, Risk Assessment, QMS

Implementation, Service Delivery, technical support

Verified : 🃞 Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Achievement-oriented and Techno-managerial professional, offering 12 plus years of rich experience in managing full spectrum of IT Programs and Projects using PMP/ Prince-2/ Waterfall/ Agile methodology in Cloud models (IAAS, SAAS, PAAS) and Non-Cloud Application Developments/ERP projects

Experienced in managing projects in Onsite -Offshore Model (US, EMEA, APAC) Regions

Forward Focused Program/ Project Manager: Experience in IT Infra Projects including initiation, planning, execution, monitoring & controlling, closing as technical support, product development, ITIL implementation, client relation, quality assurance and vendor management

Highly skilled in implementing ITILV3 based Service Delivery including Service Catalog Management, SLA Management, Change Management, Operations Gap Assessments and Process Excellence

Skilled in in the areas of ERP Business Flows both SAP & Oracle (Purchase to Pay, Order to Cash, Record to Receipt) with wide array

Work Experience

Bharti Airtel Limited, Airtel Center as Senior Project Manager-Engineering /Program Manager Oct 2018 to Aug 2020

Key Result Areas:

Leading overall AGILE and SDLC based IT Program/Projects Deliveries of Bharti Airtel B2B Engineering Team for Service Assurance and Delivery, Serve all Airtel Circles (Mobility and PRI Products) for Purchase to Pay and Order to Cash cycles

Coordinating with Partners, Customer Experience Team, Product Team and Internal Engineering Team to help building better Digital Organization

Providing strategic direction & vision for the team and leading them in the right direction to work sarter and efficiently Setting out quality standards for various operational areas, ensuring a high-quality customer experience while adhering to the SLAs and work processes

Mapping client's requirements for the product and providing best solutions involving evaluation & definition of scope of project & finalization of project requirements / needs

Identifying & implementing solutions that effectively resolve problems / issues and provide improvement

Attending daily defect meetings with Project Manager and Development Team; identifying the gaps and suggesting relevant solutions for the same

Facilitating Scrum events, promoting Agile life cycle practices leading to Scrum team success in delivering valuable product

Identifying and implementing process improvements, on boarding, reporting improvements and training as required within and across Scrum teams

Implementing Agile in projects for various large accounts, Scrum values, principles and actively applying the same in the project prior to delivery

Managing large & complex projects or multiple components of a large project involving more than one company's



Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld product

Communicating with internal / external clients to determine specific requirements and expectations; managing client expectations as an indicator of quality

Understanding process requirements and providing use cases for the business, functional & technical

Interacting with users for requirement gathering; preparing functional specifications and low-level design documents Developing & implementing plans to improve delivery standards; defining service standards and ITIL based guidelines for excellent service delivery

Facilitating smooth recovery of services and least downtime for client by leading the outage calls and effectively managing escalations

- Bharti Airtel Limited, Airtel Center as Senior Project Manager-Engineering /Program Manager Sep 2018 to Till Date
- Cap Gemini Technologies Services as Project Manager cum Service Delivery Manager Apr 2015 to Oct 2018

Project Name: Bharti Airtel Group IT Finance and SCMAVS

Client: Bharti Airtel Corporate Office | Role: Senior Project Manager

Duration: May17 - Oct18

Environment: Oracle Apps R12.1.3 for P2P, OTC, RTR, GRC Processes with IBM-FileNet, Cognos, OBIEE, REST APIs Selected Achievements:

Spearheaded projects day-to-day in accordance with Airtel HQ team Kenya

Defined and managed SLA's and Performance Measures for IT Vendors (IBM, eBus)

Assessed the timely performance of different teams working on a project & documented the progress accordingly Ensured that all programs were executed within established period and complied with the defined standards

Extended Techno-Functional Leadership from decision making to project initiation, planning till execution

Acted as SPOC for Africa SCM and Finance IT AVIS and Implementation Projects from Delhi office

Managed Escalation and CCB process for CR deliveries

Administered transition Solution amongst different Vendors via Airtel Bid Team & Stakeholders - DevOps delivery

Project Name: ITST (IT Service Transition)- Collaborative Commissioning

Client: Royal Mail Group, Chesterfield, UK Role: Project Portfolio Manager Cum Offshore Project Manager

Team Size: 20 Duration: Oct'15-Apr'17

Environment: Oracle Apps 11i/12i, PLSQL, Oracle 12c, IBMMQ, TWS, Java, REST, SOAP APIs environment, JAVA and

Microsoft Azure Stack, BSS,JIRA, DevOps CI/CD

Selected Achievements:

Recommended acceptance of the Program to Program Board in UK

Monitored and managed program level risks

Supervised change control for change requests
Administered QA Audit and QPI Scores for all projects /change request delivered

Conducted the role of Systems Integrator for the project

Ensured the Customer's acceptance in accordance with the process defined

HeadStrong via Adecco as Senior Manager

Apr 2014 to Apr 2015

Managed overall Global finance IT (Headstrong Capital Market IT) - Oracle EBS Order to Cash process in EAG (Enterprise Application Group) with following responsibilities:

Assessment of CRP for upcoming upgrade project from release 11.10.2 to 12 and involved in scoping with implementation partner E&Y overall Program Management and delivery operation via ITIL framework Planning and estimation for smaller projects as CRs, Commercial Management, Vendor and Client Management

Overall SPOC for Change Management, Issue Management and Release Management for OTC track- approve the monthly CRs for entire OTC track and represent them to overall CAB Board Meetings for next releases

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (electronics science) from University of Delhi in 2003

PG: MBA/PGDM (Computer Applications) from nielt in 2004

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Advance Diploma in Software Engineering Postgraduate Diploma in Management

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Oracle DB, SQL Server			
MySQL, Mongo DB			
UNIX (All versions), IBM-AIX			
Confluence, Jira, MS Project			
MS VISIO, TRIOKA			
SERVICENOW, FALCON, HP-ALM			
RAC, Data Guard, Golden Gate			
Oracle 12C EM			
LNUX, APACHE, MYSQL, PHP			
JAVA, JSP, EJB, JDBC, JAVASCRIPT			

NET (ASP.NET)
Microsoft Azure, AWS, Salesforce
Airtel (My Cloud)
Uipath
Git JENKINS, Docker
Oracle Apps (Release 11i to Release 12i)
SCM, HCM, SAP -FICO
MM, SD, Oracle CRM (Service CRM)
Fusion HCM, Fusion SCM
Siebel CRM, Oracle METASOLV, Tally ERP 9
Python, Angular, DLT Block chain
SDLC, AGILE (SCRUM)
Test Driven Development
Lean software development

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.